all right hello and welcome everyone
this is active infant stream number 5.1
October 16th
2024 we're going to begin with a GitHub
push I'm going to check it's been
updated in
GitHub this is also published on zenodo
so it has a DOI it's
citable and to show how to get a DOI on
zenodo I'm going to make release
0.3 right now adding a new tag
0.3 infer stream
5.1 publish
it published on GitHub
come back to
zenodo and we can find it citable it
just takes a few minutes for it to
Archive it all right so here we
are I have some topics and sections to
go through and then if you're watching
live please feel free to write any
comments and questions in in the live
chat and this should should be pretty
interesting there's going to be a lot of
ant bibliographic methods as well as
some generative AI synthetic
intelligence methods usage of perplexity
llms and so on okay so we began with a
welcome push the live stream update to
GitHub we'll give a brief overview of
the form index project I'm using cursor
version
0.423 made the new version and the repo
is list Ed here so what is the form
index project here we are in the form
index Coda which is linked in the video
description so the form
index is a multi-stage project related
to ant literature so in ant literature
there is the formis or formi depending
on how you pronounce it and this was a
effort is an effort that curated
citations related to
ants and it has uh completeness in
taxonomic areas of ant studies so a lot
of
rare ant taxonomy literature complete up
to 1996 and then not as much after and
so in for andex I'm setting out on on a
dual journey to do an analysis of formis
for its own internal sense making to
understand formis as a literature
resource itself and then also to look
more broadly towards integration of
knowledge methods for micology for ant
research and then eventually even go
beyond that with meta informat and
integrating bioinformatics and so on so
in this first part of the stream it's
going to begin with the formis analysis
which is going to briefly move through
the ant specific Parts about how the bib
text bibliography with 80 th000
references is brought in and then some
of the visualizations that come out of
the just looking at formis itself then
the second part of the methods will
focus on generative
Ai and we'll get there when we get there
so first for the formus
analysis so first Sanford sent 316
sample
citations and on October 8
I read in those just to ensure I could
get the format going he then sent over
the bib text plain text file with
880,000 records which I brought
in in the script
section with these scripts read in
formis and
visualize we'll run
them so first
reading in
forus we run
this read in
foris this was from another computer so
we'll see let's fix it on the
go meanwhile though continuing on the
report
this script reads in the bib text and
stores the Json format the generate
Target
bibliographies
subsets the 80,000 row Json database
into
uh bibliographies that mention that term
so this is what it looks like for
bioenergetics it's a Jason that's a
strict subset of the
overall we'll focus more on running the
code for the second part that I've more
recently done on this
computer the visualize form. py see if
this one works
also this one doesn't work but for the
all
formis database and for every
Target bibliography some kinds of images
are made so here's the distribution of
Records here's histogram of record
types so there's 60,000 articles 11,000
Tech reports
5,000 collections 3,500 PhD thesis 1592
books one
miscellaneous
here's authors by number of citations an
non coming through jhc deer only
slightly
behind Publications per
year so as mentioned earlier this is not
the overall number of Publications per
year in Google Scholar or literature
database this is just for formis and
this reflects what could be a really
interesting pattern to continue
exploring as we integrate other
literature searches we know that ant
Publications did continue after 1996 and
there's other citations so it's an
interesting question how do we add in
what should be the scope of this
database what what keeps it ant
relevance what's the relevance
realization for the ant literature
here's a co-authorship heat
map some of these could be cleaned up
with
uh different visual improvements it's
showing here though the number of
co-authorships between different authors
so pretty cool to identify all these
diads and in the literature we could
even look for higher order
authorship
combos here's top venues so locations
for
publishing insect soci
show evolution of the venues Through
Time
locations
wordcloud for the title hotra for
missier
and in the
abstract
wordcloud so those are the
visualizations that's just to get pretty
fast through the formis method and get
to the generative AI part where we're
going to have active inference and all
these other fun applications of of AI so
there's going to be three AI generative
AI method sections here notebook LM open
AI API and then perplexity and there's
going to be the most to explore in
perplexity so first notebook
LM here I took the target bibliography
subsets and in the Json format uploaded
to a new notebook at notebook
LM made
a made a podcast conversational style
from those citations then uploaded it to
Revit AI to make these so all mute my
local microphone and just let's see if
the audio will come through just to hear
what it's like for a
second ever looked at an anthill and
thought what's the story there
H well today yeah we're going full
Anthropologist on that I like it we're
diving into the world of the red
harvester ant okay or Pagan
Barbados okay awesome so follow on
through the links to hear the podcasts
and really promising for local text to
speech generation in the
future okay second is the closest to
what was previously done in some of the
earlier infan streams where I used the
open AI API
to concatenate the target bibliographies
with a general summarization prompt
that's the the pro summary just the
concatenated text file kind of like the
prepr grants from early on
and then script two uses the openai API
to get the summary of the literature and
then script three takes in the
literature summaries and translates into
Target languages so this is more
examples of how
different literature resources different
different text inputs can be summarized
for different audiences and in different
human languages okay now we're going to
get to the fun and the new stuff with
perplexity a
thank you Tucker for your message making
you a moderator for that
one I hope you enjoy your new Ranch
Tucker okay so just to get familiar with
what perplexity is here I pasted a
prompt into perplexity doai write a
comprehensive summary of the RX INF fur.
JL package and perplexity goes through a
series of steps it does online searches
finds relevant chunks of information and
then it writes this report responding to
the prompt with internet information
including these code boxes so I'm
showing that because what this next
section is going to do is essentially
send this exact prompt among others and
then interface with it through the
scripts so here's another example create
a comprehensive Grant proposal outlined
for the NSF safety security and privacy
of Open Source ecosystems safe o program
and then again similarly it just thinks
okay which which ecosystem how about
tensorflow so enhancing security and
privacy in the tensorflow ecosystem and
then writes the grant making up the
information also on the notebook LM a
friend just shared with me
illuminate which you can do the
literature search this is illuminate.
goole.com do the literature search so
here I have it look up active
inference and then had it pull in these
four papers so it's taking one more step
for you whereas with notebook LM you had
to download the PDF and upload them
let's now listen for the first time
to
illuminate I'm going to turn off my
microphone and it will play from the
computer
this conversation is powered by Google
illuminate check out illuminate.
google.com for more Welcome to our
discussion on active inference a
fascinating framework for understanding
how agents make decisions in uncertain
environments we'll be exploring several
research papers that delve into the
intricacies of active inference
comparing it to the well-established
field of reinforcement learning what are
the core tenets of active inference and
how does it differ from reinforcement
learning active inference rooted in the
free energy principle posits that agents
act to minimize their surprise the
uncertainty about the world unlike
reinforcement learning which focuses on
maximizing a reward signal active
inference aims to minimize free energy a
measure encompassing both prediction
error and the complexity of the agent's
internal model
this another another one pretty cool
though illuminate. gooogle okay in gen
24 was with different kinds of calls to
action translated into a lot of language
if people want to look in that
repo okay
so where were we with
perplexity
so
uh I did several things in the report on
the 13th and then in the several days
since several other things have happened
so I'm going to just skip over the
earlier parts that were written about
perplexity and we'll pop over to the
documentation for the API and then look
at how it's being used in the package
now so where things are out right now
pending the rest of this stream of
course communicating with the formis
stakeholders get their feedback get
others feedback open science Etc then we
have the analysis within for
me looking at how we can do all kinds of
augmented analyses
within the database as it stands in July
2024 snapshot and then also go beyond
for me July 2024 snapshot so adding in
new literature connecting with the
species ID perplexity searches Etc
fabric integration kind of like was
happening in the previous infer an
street so okay all this is open source
in the form index
repo quick look at the perplexity
API very simple docs
page you get $5 a month for paying $20 a
month wow and there's a really short
simple example that gets you going here
are the supported models they have at
this
time they have several of sizes of this
perplexity sonar llama 3.1 base at 870
and 405 billion
parameters they have and and uh they
have several perplexity chat models
these are chat they're not do online
searches and then there's the instruct
open source models
they mention the rate limit 50 a minute
we might hit that pricing is shown here
and each one of these
requests seems to be costing using the
large model I think in most cases the
the the the goldilock medium one each of
these was maybe a tenth of a cent or a
fifth of a
Cent and I'm sure a cheaper one would be
a fifth back cost and and so on so super
worth it for for what we're getting all
right here we
go let's pop into the perplexity methods
folder okay that was the formus analysis
goals accessible rigorous applicable
micology notebook LM
open AI API for the
translation now perplexity API
so um test perplexity API is a short
script that tests the network
connectivity simple perplexity is where
you can paste in your private
key it's just simpler and keep it all in
one just with their example of starting
so this is if you want to study the simp
EST perplexity call you can make so now
here we get an llm keys. key it's in
ignore so it's not sync to GitHub and it
has the perplexity API key so there are
uh as the simple perplexity
shows you can send your message with a
system prompt and a user prompt so this
is kind of the context or the character
system prompt and then the specific user
request
so first the user prompts this is what
somebody would type in they're in a Json
called user promps do Jason and they're
numbered as well as given a short name
and the full prompt so here prompt one
short name is climate change impact and
the prompt is conduct a comprehensive
meta analysis of studies published in
the last year on the impact of climate
change on Ant species diversity and then
extra information you can say outp
output in this style or make sure you do
a ton of research um and so there's
several dozen the first few dozen are
ants related then applications of ants
what's the role of neurotransmitters
brain
regions then prompt 2425 we get into
doing meta analyses of the career of
Professor Deborah Gordon and Professor
Tim Lings faay we we can add more if
people have any requests for prompts
please write them in the chat and I'll
add it here uh doing meta analyses on
different areas of ant Biometrics like
relatedness within and across colonies
phenotypic correlation
measures then now prompt 33 3435 we're
getting into specific ant groups doing a
meta analysis of studies published in
the last three
years so cotus formica tholi adaa
solenopsis monore
laus okapa pogam mirx Barbados that's
genus and
species and then non Barbados pogam
species then we get into the regional we
got NorthEast Southwest USA Pacific
Northwest agricultural ants Northern
California
ants Davis D Davis agricultural ants
Davis Urban ant ecology Davis invasive
ants
ant symbolism ant wisdom ants and
Contemporary Art ants indigenous wisdom
stewardship then 65 takes a a bit of a
Twist here we get more into prompts that
are not necessarily related to act uh to
to ants but some of them do as well rela
rela to the active inference theoretical
foundations recent developments
applications to ant behavior of active
emerence PhD proposals for active
inference foraging simulators for active
inference recent events related to
active
inference writing step-by-step tutorials
this one's going to be fun to look
at giving comprehensive overview of
basing mechanics Quantum active
inference writing a a summary and
stepbystep on RX infer JL Julia
package writing who's on first dialogues
writing Grant proposals fire risk
assessments and county level fire risk
assessments thanks Tucker
enjoy that's user prompts system prompts
there are fewer but if someone suggests
one just write it in the live chat these
are also identified with a number and a
short name and a longer description so
here's a Mycologist some several ant
researcher roles programmer complex
system scientist local journalist
enthusiastic undergrad
system promps seven and eight are
questions from the innovator's catechism
at the early ideation and then later
pitch stage so they're going to respond
with question and answer structured
information which we'll look at and some
other areas so then perplexity
py you list the short name of the target
system prompts and then the target user
prompts so we could add one if if
somebody types another user prompt um
just let's do Lake County fire risk just
to show what it looks
like say
perplexity run it as Python 3
perplexity so where the outputs already
exist then
uh it skips it for that combination so
it looks like that was already
done let's see if it'll autoc complete
or let's just pick a user prompt that
hasn't been
done let's do
foli formica recent studies
so systems uh uh innovator catechisms
pitch the outputs existed for some of
these user prompts
already then it hits formica recent
studies which is a new one so it's going
to send that off to
perplexity um while that's chugging away
I'm going to go over to the GitHub and
we're going to look at a few of the
outputs of the the primary artifacts
themselves so just the outputs of the
perplexity different characters doing
these
different kinds of syntheses and then we
will look at the semantic and linguistic
methods that analyze the folders of
documents the markdown output folder is
nested into the different
roles so let's compare the innovator's
catechism with the complex system
scientist
okay here we have complex system
scientist recent events here's iy number
four this was a event I don't know if
the dates were correct but that did
happen in 20
23 there's some Institute quarterly
round table so it's o o over learning on
that or somehow it came to to learn
about that one live stream here's basy
mechanics
overview this is written like
a curriculum
explainer here's the career meta
analysis of Professor Deborah Gordon
early career topics methodologies key
findings this is a different Deborah
Gordon both Deborah Gordons so it wasn't
sure so it
wrote about Deborah M Gordon the
Mycologist and then other Deborah Gordon
as
well here's Lake County California warn
your fire
risk current fire conditions historical
fire
data climate weather pattern vegetation
fuel load topography human factors
infrastructural
vulnerability fire management
resources prevention mitigation
strategies future projections economic
impact ecological consideration
Community preparedness postfire recovery
actionable recommendations no citations
provided
here's overview of RX and
fur this is the perplexity example on
the web interface that I showed
earlier here it is just in GitHub and we
can test running this but this is pretty
much what it looks like and if it's
gener if it's pulling from the coin toss
example this should be good
here's
the
grants proposal for safe
osse again that was a one where I showed
the real web
interface and then let's see the who's
on
first so this one makes a who's on on
first about hurricane
Milton I
guess that's what it
thought current events were now if we
look over in the innovator's catechism
system prompt folder there should be
some differences
here
here the output format is requested to
be the project
catechism so with interesting madeup
team names which we'll see I think a few
of we see the catechism format of
situation problem and this the
entrepreneurial pitch catechism
specifically situation in terms of key
problems user segments Alternatives
early adopters the mission and the value
proposition potential Avenues of
approach and the resources that they're
uh associated with advantages risks Fe
abilities channels Milestones metrics
cost benefit big picture admin folder
bibliography here it's a pitch about a
project to study active inference ant
Behavior and the first citation is a
real
paper here we have innovator's catechism
for the foraging simulation
so and it
includes some code
methods here's a pitch for the basian
mechanics SO pitching why we would want
to have this basian mechanics explainer
on
Border looking at these citations open
up all four of them
we
have relevant
paper with a incorrect citation ramstead
at all rather than stiva devel at
all second paper ramstead at all
20123 here incorrectly as Royal Society
publishing 2023 title is
correct
here's a conference 2024 2024
okay here's a
PDF Zuckerman and George chem archive so
citations not fully accurate but
citations real links
nonetheless um
here we get to the
grant proposal so it's aose or safe O
type application for here it it settled
on Linux kernel open source
ecosystem so it lays out using the
catechism format the essential value
proposition Avenues of approach all the
information about the grant like hm
catechism for DARPA this is using the
innovator's catechism pitch for safe o
for NSF in a
hypothetical
world so each of these folders depending
on how the prompts
interact there's really interesting
outputs in terms of maybe maybe the
undergrad making
the PDP p mdp active inference
simulation maybe this is the best
so that's where the perplexity so here
it was from running the perplexity
py they all went for the formica recent
studies just while this was happening so
let's push that update
formica
005 push it
now let's look at local
journalist formica so this just happened
now meta analysis of recent studies on
the genus formica 21 to
23 here's a table looking pretty nice
with two studies on
formica table with one study on social
parasitism one study on foraging
activity trophic relationships social
parasitism host parasite different
methodologies
significant results and impact
controversies debates conclusion and the
formatted
references pretty cool let's look at the
futurist for
formica here it's a different format we
see more of a general summary of the
state-ofthe-art on the monine polygon
research
agenda we don't see those tables broken
out the same way and there's not a
strong futurist bent so it could be
some interaction of the model the system
prompt the user prompt of course all
this needs to
be
checked and could be checked with
with synthetic as well as manual human
means let's see what the
Mycologist what what would the
Mycologist say when it walked into a NSF
Grant application
so it wasn't
included because it was taken off these
targets so
here add
in
comprehensive let's just check from user
from system
prompts it's called comprehensive mology
paste it in save it clear it run
perplexity
oh maybe there already
is
that okay so that's the combinatorics of
generating combinations of the user and
the system prompt
this is going to now get into the
visualization section that's new from
the
report uh visualization methods.
py is a nice
long 590 line methods file
visualization. py brings in those
methods set the input and the output
folder make the directory for the output
if it's not there set up the
logging load in some of the text
processing modules pre-process perform
some of the
analyses output several groups of
visualizations group one is related to
Dimension reduction
visualizations group two is related to
enhanced PCA principal component
analysis
visualization uh that was part of group
one group two word importance in PCA
group three is more text analysis so I'm
going to delete the folder
visualizations right click open
integrated interal Python
visualization so this is what it's going
to look like when it
runs it's going to Output how many
markdown files it's taken in 158 so if
we added more to perplexity py we could
do some of that we could add another
and then it would output more and then
rerunning visualization would pick up on
those new
ones okay so there's nothing in
visualizations yet it's doing the
analyses and then it's going to start to
spit one by one saved images into the
visualizations
folder we will look at those
and see what it shows us about
outputs in terms of their
semantics and in terms of how the system
prompt and the user prompt
interact and how we might use
that so the analysis gets
slower as
more
um documents come into play I'll just
show here's system prompt. Json contr a
control I so bring it in the compon ER
add
a system prompt
for an expert
Chef who
outputs dinner
menus with Rich relevance for any
prompt output is
always epic dinner
Adventures
though so this is a way to use cursor in
this informal way to write a well
structured prompt
13 so it's going to first write it in
this side window that's kind of and then
it scans over and now culinary
Adventurer so I take culinary Adventurer
go back to perplexity
systems
prompt culinary Venture it I think
that's super Maven but still it it knew
that I wanted that
one I'm going to terminate the
visualization effort for now called the
Python 3 perplexity so now here's the
new the ones that were already done are
skipped and the new combinations are
being sent off right click opening the
integrated
terminal Python
visualization other outputs was just
earlier
texts from from a simpler time from a
different
time all I'll delete these and they're
they're always there on git but I'll
delete them for
now Pusher get
update and then visualizations are going
to start to come through and this is
going to help us get a
handle uh I'm also going to resync the
cursor context oh it was it
resn
great okay introduce perplexity py
explain the structure of user and system
prompts looked at simple and
test explaining how different kinds of
prompts are handled let's look at the
visualizations and then we'll go to the
next steps so again here's
visualization. py
all
right
so they're now
getting output to the folder I'll just
let them all
run let's just start with LSA
plot so here's two components looks like
partially labeled
LSA component one document semantics PCA
3D plot okay
cool interesting color
scheme PCA cumulative
variance so it looks like only five PCA
components are retained we could
increase that
number but it's showing the accumulation
of variance and we're not saturated yet
so to capture more the variance it would
probably make sense to add more than
five principal
component
terms okay confidence
intervals this is the mean TF IDF score
which is a document frequency uh inverse
document frequency so here we have ant
and inference with higher scores and
then some of these other ones with lower
scores LSA topics okay here we have
different ways of doing topic
modeling topic one has to do with time
passing on graphs and reactive message
passing in the Julia package as well as
Lou Castello for some reason from the
who's on first
probably topic two having to do with
active inference ontology terms Quantum
active
inference topic three having to do with
Collective Behavior free
energy four having to do with the the
other Deborah Gordon talking about the
environmental the World Resources
modeling here's linkx veyor and security
so okay
cool here's the principal component
analysis with the ien
terms so we looked at the cumulative
variance plot
before the scre plot is showing the
decreasing fraction of variance that
each of these
components
add
let's let's update
visualization
methods ensure to include 50
PCA
Dimensions okay we'll keep looking at it
there's the principal component
analysis oh we we were high
up this is pretty cool here we have five
of the different principal components
with
colors and then we can see okay fire is
cross-listed
on explaining the variance fractionation
of blue and green
whereas inference is only loaded up in
on fraction
two and then that's shown here there're
separate but also there's some that are
cross-listed let's see how that edit
went okay
interesting looks like it's deleting a
bunch of
stuff let's accept it save it
clear run the visualization
again so
now these culinary Adventures are still
pumping in the
background
so now we have 169 markdown files
whereas in the previous time there was
158 or something like that so it's going
to redo
these they might be changing right from
underneath
us
okay prompt distribution here's
different system prompts and and user
prompts and different words in
them here's a funny
visualization document length across the
system prompts so here we could say okay
the expert programmer has a shorter
document length on average
and then here's the statistical tests
and the the P values for the
Anova it's not statistically significant
out a 05
Alpha term frequency here's term
frequency inference ant
fire term
Network so here we have terms and their
connections with the co-occurrence
module je so this is a lot like Gene
cooccurrence based upon expression
levels here's term frequency heat
map so we can see red is more usage more
unique strong
usage light yellow is less strong unique
usage so fire is a word that's either
mentioned a
lot or it's
not there's other terms such as system
or research or use that have more
variable
use Tey
plot word
cloud word
importance here's the top 20 words in
each of those
modules and then a word cloud for them
and similar for PCA and for the
LSA
um uh this most recent rerunning brought
in
the culinary
Adventurer so there they are culinary
Adventurer that's just showing how you
can
add to the system
prompts bring it into perplexity
py have it combinatorically
generating using the perplexity API
call so then
we'll uh and
then meanwhile you can be rerunning the
visualization method so here there's an
error picks the
error to fix the error image size of
9,000 by 90,000 pixels is too large it
must be less than 2 to the 16th in each
Direction
w because we asked about retaining 50
dimensions
save it clear
it delete the visualizations
folder run it
again we could
parallelize the API
call get closer to that rate limit 50
per minute
let's look at some of the
outputs
reload markdown
output culinary
Adventurer that's the new one
so we all we
asked this is what is so fascinating
this is really worth the
Ponder who's on first of current events
I've seen this several
times this
topic wow look at the topics
here
vaccine Elon Musk
artificial
intelligence
hurricanes
meta Mark
Zuckerberg Putin Vladimir
Putin
Google and it's all unpacked that's not
a recipe that's not a menu fire
assessment not a menu
fora the The Prompt did work so here the
societal Symphony of fora ants a dinner
concept Colony awakening's first dish
appetizer forager's Bounty Super Salad
super Colony soup main course Queen's
Feast pallet cleanser aphid's nectar
wow
wow Chef's
commentary with
references analysis of active inference
events
same outputs as others
okay let's check back looks like the
PCA let's check back at the
PCA here we
go
cool so now we have uh cumulative
variance rare faction
plot and we can see a lot more
richly the relationship with these
different
terms loading heat map here's a thousand
features
retained you can see some patterns of
positive and
negative
here we see different PCA plotting
different PCA
plotting there's some methods that look
at where things start to bottom out or
change like break
points here's the the terms that are
associated with the top 50 principle
components term Network
so that's pretty cool that perplexity
can do these
searches
and pull information from the
internet let's add another user
prompt
right with
code a
workshop a Hands-On
Workshop oriented towards applying
active
inference in the bio
Regional
setting at a
prompt that will write with
code comprehensive Hands-On Workshop
oriented towards applying active
inference and bio Regional
settings B
professional the
outcome should be
Standalone and ready for deployment
so prompt
81 move that
over
there run perplexity
here we go so skips over what's already
been done first one that it hits is
innovators catechism pitch the first one
in the
list catching on the first one that is
undone so once that first one comes out
I'll push it we'll check it out on
GitHub it'll be the value proposition
from a innovator's catechism pitch
perspective for the Biore Regional
active inference
Workshop 41
seconds okay
push
it innovator's catechism
pitch it's uploading all the
images reload it
bi Reginal AI Workshop
gmail.com situation key
problems lack of integrated
decision-making tools inefficient
Resource Management limited
collaboration user segments ecologists
environmental managers data scientists
alternative traditional statistical
models which are static and often static
and do not account for dynamic
environmental changes machine learning
approaches while powerful these may not
provide the same level of
interpretability and integration with
ecological principles as active
inference early adopters research
institutions government agencies NOS
Community groups Mission value
proposition to provide a comprehensive
and practical understanding of active
inference principles and their
application to Biore Regional management
enabling participants to make more
informed sustainable and adaptive
decisions Avenues of
approach theoretical Foundation
mathematical
framework computational implementation
data collection and processing
pre-processing model building and
simulation case studies integration with
existing management practices future
directions Advanced topics resources
computational resources data and Human
Resources advantages unified framework
and interpretability risks complexity
and data quality
feasibility given the advantages and the
growing interest in active this project
is highly feasible the workshop can
leverage existing research and tools and
the facilitators can provide the
necessary support to ensure participants
understand and apply the concepts
effectively channels academic and
professional networks online
platforms Milestones metrics
Milestones cost and Benefit Big
Picture Maria Dr Maria Rafa
day one theoretical foundations
mathematical framework morning session
afternoon session day two compliment
computational implementation and data
collection day three model building
simulation case study day four
integration future directions Advanced
topics follow-up
exercises wow
expert
programmer ants Contemporary
Art ants geopolitics and social
structure
expert programmer ant
foraging local journalist
New Mexico fire risk looks a lot like
the other
ones
okay so that
is basically all this has been a
checkpoint for the forem
andex
project there's some ant specific
directions there's some Science
Education communication generative AI
Plus+ plus lot
of fun and
interesting methods that people may find
useful it's all open
source
code I'll push the final up we we'll
just return to the next steps and and
close here so if anyone has a a comment
or question for to to do otherwise let's
just cover these last
steps um this is kind of a random
thought having situational awareness of
when are we in the infrastructural core
when are we working with ad Jason schema
we're changing the schema is going to
have big
repercussions where are we scouting or
playing or researching on the edge and
Beyond where we can change something
like a cold is z and it won't influence
other
things uh get the feedback from formis
improve the methods integrate with
species ID do perplexity searches for
all species groups of ants and maybe
Beyond integrate with
fabric uh there's no written questions
yet if anyone has ideas leave a comment
get in
touch I hope this was of epistemic and
pragmatic value for you check out the
repo check it all out
end of number
5.1 and
there it
is all
right and there's the Zen
no.3 version from the beginning of the
stream pretty cool awesome times okay
thanks for watching looking forward to
people's feedback where it all goes till
next time bye